Contact

Duren Tiga Jakarta Selatan +6281383207771 (Mobile) farid.enal@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/enalfarid (LinkedIn) enalfarid.digital (Personal)

Top Skills

E-commerce Leadership Strategic Planning

Languages

English

Certifications

Finalis Bank Mandiri Hackathon WTH 2019 - Scrum Master

Training Aplikasi Umrah SISKOPATUH

PCI DSS Training 2017

Honors-Awards

Finalis Top 50 Scrum Master Hackathon Bank Mandiri WTH 2019

Zainal Farid

Founder at Lintas Inovasi Digital

Greater Jakarta Area, Indonesia

Summary

Deeply passionate about human, culture and technology which helps me a lot in producing ideas. Falling in love with research and digital transformation. Advocate team collaborations towards the ability to continuously adapt to changes and drive sensible disruptions for business sustainability and profitability.

Experience

Lintas Inovasi Digital Founder May 2018 - Present Jakarta

- Shape company vision and determine quarterly roadmap
- Build and lead team consisting of engineers, products and marketing
- Create annual financial budget needed to run the company

Caryta

Managing Partner
August 2017 - December 2017 (5 months)

Greater Jakarta Area, Indonesia

Caryta is an early stage tech based start-up in Southeast Asia. We based in Jakarta, Indonesia, and have our own company building although we are new comers in this business.

Caryta is a travel marketplace especially for Holiday Tour and Open Trips.

Our mission is to empower the Indonesian local trips provider and to ease the booking process of tour or trips package for the traveller. We offer you a safe and affordable travel option.

Our dream is to connecting you to millions of beautiful places to travel in the world especially in Indonesia, a challenging and ambitious roadmap.

Our engine is the energetic staff member that passionate with travelling business. Caryta is a tech based start-up that enjoying having fun while

Page 1 of 3

traversing the roads together, which one of our values. Disrupt the travelling world, break the same old!

ABU GROUP

Product Manager

August 2014 - December 2017 (3 years 5 months)

Greater Jakarta Area, Indonesia

Responsible for guiding the success of a product and leading the crossfunctional team that is responsible for improving it.

Sets the strategy, roadmap, and feature definition for a product or product line. responsible for defining the why, when, and what of the product that the engineering team builds.

Surya Cipta Pacific Senior Manager Infrastructure October 2011 - November 2014 (3 years 2 months) Greater Jakarta Area, Indonesia

Migrating to AWS cloud, Softlayer Bare Metal Servers.

Linux server maintenance e.g. upgrade (include data migration), patch, repair, backup and restore for web, mail and database server

Linux server installation and system security

Linux server user administrator

Maintain server inventories (hardware, software, license, client, etc)

Troubleshooting server problem

Greater Jakarta Area, Indonesia

OLX Indonesia (olx.co.id) System Administrator October 2010 - October 2011 (1 year 1 month)

Responsible to office/internal IT operation, network engineer

Visi Akses Komunika System Administrator November 2005 - May 2010 (4 years 7 months) Greater Jakarta Area, Indonesia

Administrator Education Portal Telkom Divre VII Makassar
Trainer Community Development S&T Telkom Divre VII Makassar
Aplication Programmer
Network Engineer

Education

STMIK Handayani Makassar Bachelor's degree, Informatic Technology · (2000 - 2004)

SMA Negeri 2 Ambon Sains · (1995 - 1998)